(The Shadow Sovereign)
I slept really well last night.
These are rewards for you.
Looks like you truly see me as...
Well, that's fine.
Thank you for these gifts, Your Highness.
Please help me pawn off all of these.
Use the money we get from them
to set up more soup kitchens for the refugees outside the city.
And buy some books
and writing supplies for our fellow students.
Where do you get them?
Of course, the source is clean.
Let's just call it taking from the rich to help the poor.
But let's put that aside for now.
Today,
I have a "taking from the rich for the poor" plan to discuss with you.
You just joined the Ministry of Revenue, and you're already risking it.
The one who really gets me is you, Le Sheng.
Now that you've landed an influential partner,
why bother putting yourself at risk?
All these gold and silver ingots
are really just charity from that person.
But the only ones I can truly trust with my life are my closest friends.
Le Sheng, you're different.
Tell me. What's the plan?
- You want to investigate the Crown Prince's private treasury? - Yes.
While checking the accounts,
I found that the Crown Prince hired many refugees
under the guise of disaster relief,
and paid them in grains instead of money.
That was the Crown Prince's scheme all along.
The only way now is to follow Commander Cui's grain transport soldiers
to locate the Crown Prince's private treasury.
That's the only solution.
- Stay alert. - Yes, Commander.
But even if you find the private treasury,
how can you prove
that the grains inside belong to the Ministry of Revenue?
Don't worry, Your Highness.
In the latest batch of grains for canal repairs,
I mixed in special rice bran as a marker.
When it enters the Crown Prince's private treasury,
I'll definitely be able to trace it.
- How dare you... - I know this is risky.
But for the sake of the country and to ease His Majesty's burdens,
my own safety
isn't worth mentioning.
I promise that this action of mine
will never implicate the Ministry of Revenue or Your Highness.
You're truly a loyal and brave Top Scholar Shen.
I really didn't misjudge you.
Go ahead and investigate without worry.
If you need anything,
I'll fully support you.
Thank you, Your Highness.
(Since you want to take that risk yourself, )
(don't blame me for it.)
Your Majesty, your medicine is here.
Princess Zhao Yang requests an audience with His Majesty!
I, Zhao Yang, your daughter, wish Your Majesty good health.
I am not well.
I'm deeply troubled by that.
Troubled?
You look obedient on the surface.
But your hand has reached all the way
toward the top scholar from humble origins whom I've chosen.
I started the imperial exam and promoted those from humble backgrounds
to bring new blood to the court.
Not to send them to their deaths.
You pushed Shen Xiao into the Ministry of Revenue.
What are you trying to do?
Father.
The noble families are taking advantage of the disaster to hoard goods,
profiting off the country's misfortune.
The Crown Prince is misled by the noble families,
and doesn't understand your good intentions.
With guidance from you,
I know I should help the Crown Prince plan more.
The drought is severe now,
and the people are restless.
I hope to use Shen Xiao's abilities
to recover the treasury for the court and bring peace to the nation.
I also hope the Crown Prince can discern people's true character
and understand your good intentions.
So, you still remember.
I wouldn't dare forget.
The sky was glowing with rosy clouds,
and golden light filled the heavens.
The people are full of complaints
after I started those massive construction projects.
These auspicious signs you used from the heavens
came at just the right time.
What reward do you want?
I don't wish for any reward.
I only wish to ease your burdens.
Speak.
While I was overseeing the construction of Qianfo Temple,
I happened to intercept a memorial from the clerk
of the Ministry of Revenue, Shen Qing Zhi.
It was filled with slander and false accusations against the Crown Prince.
I was shocked and burned it right away.
But unexpectedly, this person recently fell off a cliff.
I'm afraid there's more to this story.
If someone with an agenda uses it,
it could damage the court's reputation.
A lowly official
trying to frame the Crown Prince
is not worth pitying.
Zhao Yang, you did the right thing.
You're even
smarter than I thought.
The Crown Prince
needs someone as wise as you and knows what's important by his side.
From now on,
you must advise and support the Crown Prince more.
I hope
you will always use
your cleverness in the right place.
Yes, Father. I won't let you down.
(The Crown Prince treats lives like they're nothing.)
(He's not fit to be the future heir.)
(If we really want to replace him, )
(His Majesty needs to catch him making an even bigger mistake.)
(This isn't something a righteous little official)
(can pull off with a few impeachment letters.)
(You have to make His Majesty)
(unable to tolerate him anymore.)
Even if it's for the Crown Prince and the country,
letting Shen Xiao investigate
is still way too risky.
I can allow him to try.
But
you need to support him from the sidelines.
I will keep Shen Xiao safe.
I'll take my leave.
(Shen Xiao.)
(It's confirmed that the noble families are manipulating the Crown Prince.)
(If you die, )
(it'll completely turn the Crown Prince against the Emperor.)
(Whether you solve the Yongtong Canal issue or not, )
(you'll still help weaken the noble families.)
(Wannian Granary)
- Stay alert. - Roger that.
(This is not right.)
(These aren't grains from the Ministry of Revenue.)
Aren't you Censor Shen?
You sneaked into the Princess's granary.
What secrets are you trying to find in these rice sacks?
I've really underestimated you, Top Scholar.
Since you won't show your true face,
don't blame us if you get hurt.
- Commander is hurt. - Stop him!
Commander, are you okay?
- Go after him! - Roger that!
I didn't expect you could ride so well.
I didn't expect you could actually injure Prince Consort Cui.
Stop right there!
Get off your horse.
Wait up for me!
Turn around.
Commander Cui, long time no see. Hope you've been well.
This is the Map Commissioner Badge bestowed by His Majesty.
Map Commissioner?
Are you the Seventh Prince?
I, Cui Jin Zhi,
pay my respects to Your Highness.
It's been a long time.
Your Highness, what brings you to the wilderness so late at night?
I'm observing the stars tonight to map the land.
Commander Cui, who are you chasing after
so late at night with your troops?
I'm after a wanted criminal.
Have you seen anyone suspicious around?
I haven't seen anyone.
Commander Cui, are you suspecting me?
I wouldn't dare.
If you wouldn't dare,
then stop following me.
Commander.
How come I've never heard of the Seventh Prince?
He was born with white hair.
So he was seen as a bad omen.
He was ordered to leave the palace seven years ago.
Why would he be back right this moment?
And just when Shen Xiao escaped.
There's something off about him.
Have someone follow him in secret.
Find out where he lives and who he's meeting with. Go.
Yes, Commander.
The one who saved Shen Xiao
must be a woman.
(Princess Zhao Yang Residence)
You really think Cui Jin Zhi is that dumb?
Do you know whose private treasury you broke into tonight?
It's mine.
How can you laugh about that?
Didn't you say you didn't want to die?
You said you wouldn't care about me anymore.
So why risk your life to save me today?
His Majesty ordered me to protect you.
If you hadn't received an imperial order,
would you really let me die?
Don't be mad, Your Highness.
I was reckless today.
That was why I fell into their trap.
I should've been more careful.
What's the point of saying that now?
What's wrong? Let me see.
So, you do worry about me after all.
I'm not wasting my time on you.
You idiot! I'm the Prince Consort.
Do you think the Princess's chamber can keep me out?
Move aside.
Hurry up and hide inside.
Who's inside?
What are you doing? Get in there!
Get in there now.
Zhao Yang! Who's in the chamber?
Prince Consort, you can't go in!
Zhao Yang!
Seems like you've forgotten
about my rules.
How dare you barge into my residence at night?
Someone broke into your granary tonight.
For your safety,
I have to check things out.
You have your men guarding the granary.
But someone still managed to slip in and out of it?
Looks like this person is no ordinary thief.
Just some petty crook.
If I catch him,
I'll tear him to pieces.
Are you hurt?
The one who hurt me was probably Shen Xiao.
You never sleep in your outer robe.
Did you go out tonight?
You have never stayed overnight at my residence.
You sound like you know me pretty well.
The person who saved Shen Xiao
was you.
Prince Consort, are you out of your mind?
If I were helping Shen Xiao,
I wouldn't be so dumb as to send him to the heavily guarded granary
and then save him myself.
Prince Consort, this accusation
isn't very clever.
You're always suspicious of me and Shen Xiao.
Do you want me to get caught
so you can make room for your new mistress?
I don't have a mistress anymore.
I've already sent Qing Luo away. There won't be anyone else!
Forget it.
I'm pretty sure the person who saved Shen Xiao was a woman.
She looked a lot like you.
Prince Consort, you can't even remember what I look like?
I'm not joking with you.
The Crown Prince hates Shen Xiao most of all.
- If you keep... - Was it really Shen Xiao who hurt you?
Then he's actually quite capable.
Li Shu.
If I didn't know you hated me,
I would've thought
that you were just jealous.
You're hurt too.
You should head back and rest.
I'm hurt.
Are you not going to take care of me anymore?
In the past...
In the past, you used to help me apply medicine on my wounds.
That was in the past.
Back then, I wanted to get close to you.
That's why I waited outside the Cold Palace every day to bandage you.
That way, I would have a chance to sit in on the Grand Tutor's lessons.
I won the Crown Prince's favor by ghostwriting for him.
I was just waiting for a chance to leave the Cold Palace.
No.
Impossible.
It was just sparring.
How could the Crown Prince go so hard on you?
I'm fine.
His Highness is my lord, I'm his subject.
A subject can't blame their lord.
In the end, whether it's punishment or reward,
it's all the lord's grace.
Those of us close to him
are no different from his hounds or hawks.
As long as the master is happy,
that's all that matters to us.
- That's not right. - Why is it not right?
A ruler
should lead with virtue and win people over with kindness.
Even the Crown Prince
shouldn't take pleasure in humiliating others.
And he shouldn't look down on
those who serve him loyally.
You may be the Crown Prince's study companion,
but you're still your own person.
Li Shu.
Once I earn some military merit next year,
I'll go and beg His Majesty for a favor.
When that time comes, no one will be able to bully you.
Not even the Crown Prince.
The battlefield is dangerous.
You have to be careful.
For you,
I promise I'll come back safe.
We weren't like this
in the past.
You must have remembered it wrongly.
I'm just a scheming,
lowly orphan who crawled out of the Cold Palace.
Who do you think you are?
Aren't you just a lowly orphan who crawled out of the Cold Palace?
- I... - On our wedding night,
you made that very clear.
How did it come to this between us?
Let go of me!
Let go!